Now, we'll look at how to use one random variable to predict another random variable.
接下来我们将学习如何使用一个随机变量预测另一个随机变量
We'll cover the basics of regression as this forms the basis for
我们将介绍回归的基础知识
several models that are used to analyze stock returns over time.
这将为我们学习分析股票收益的其他模型打下基础
If we want to estimate the price of a house,
如果我们想估算房价
we may assume that home buyers are willing to pay more for a bigger house,
我们可能会假定买房者愿意为更大的房屋支付更高的金额
all other things being equal.
所有其他参数保持不变
So, we may find data on the area covered by each house as well as its price.
我们可以计算每个房屋的占地面积以及房价
We want to find a coefficient that we can multiply by the area,
我们想要计算一个系数 用它乘以面积
then add a constant term,
然后加上一个常数项
which we refer to as the intercept.
称之为截距
This is the equation for a straight line.
这就是直线方程
Fortunately, we don't have to guess the best values for the coefficient and intercept.
幸运的是 我们不需要猜测系数和截距的最佳值
When we plot the price against the area,
在绘制房价与面积图时
we can draw a line that tries its best to pass through most of the points.
我们可以画一条尽量能够经过大部分点的直线
We can measure how well the line fits the data by
然后测量点与直线之间的垂直距离
measuring the vertical difference between the point and the line.
看看这条线与数据的拟合效果
An optimal regression line is one that manages to reduce these differences.
最佳回归线能够尽量降低这些差异
This process that finds the optimal regression line is called ordinary least squares.
寻找最佳回归线的流程称为普通最小二乘法
Even after we find the best regression line,
即使找到最佳回归线
we can expect to see differences between the data points and the line.
数据点与直线之间依然可能存在差异
These differences between the best fit regression line at
每个点与最佳拟合回归线之间的差异
each point are called residuals or error terms.
称为残差或误差项
In other words, the residual is the difference between the actual value,
换句话说 残差等于实际值
and the predicted value.
与预测值之间的差异
We can check if the residuals follow a normal distribution.
我们可以检查残差是否遵守正态分布
If the residuals follow a normal distribution with
如果残差遵守正态分布
a mean of zero and a constant standard deviation,
均值为零 标准差为常数
then these residuals can be considered random.
那么这些残差可以视作随机值
By random, I mean that the model's predicted value is equally
随机是指模型的预测值
likely to be higher or lower than the actual value.
高于或低于随机值的概率是一样的
If however, the average of the residuals is not zero,
但是 如果残差的平均值不为零
this gives us a hint that the model has a bias in its prediction errors.
那么表明模型的预测误差存在偏差
One way to improve our model is to look for other independent variables.
改进模型的一种方式是寻找其他自变量
This is called multiple regression,
称为多元回归
when we use more than one independent variable to predict a dependent variable.
即用多个自变量预测一个因变量
Now that we fit a regression model,
拟合回归模型后
we want to check if we can rely on it for future predictions.
我们需要检查是否能用它进行未来预测
One measure of our model's ability to fit the data is the R-squared value.
衡量模型能否拟合数据的一种方法是 R 平方值
The R-squared is a metric that ranges from zero to one.
R 平方这个指标在0 到 1 之间
R-squared of one means that all the variation in the dependent variable,
R 平方为 1 表示因变量的所有变化
can be explained by all the variation in the independent variables.
都可以用自变量的所有变化进行解释
A better metric is the adjusted R-squared,
调整后 R 平方是更好的指标
which helps us to find the minimum combination of
它可以帮助我们找到
independent variables that are most relevant for our model.
与模型最相关的自变量最小组合
Another way to check our model,
检查模型的另一种方式是
is by performing an F-test.
执行 F 检验
The F-test checks whether our coefficients and
F 检验会检查系数和截距是否不为零
intercepts are not zero, and therefore, meaningful.
因此有意义
If we get a P-value of 0.05 or smaller,
如果 p 值等于或小于 0.05
we can assume that our parameters are not zero.
那么我们认为参数不为零
When parameters are not zero,
如果参数不为零
then we can say that our model describes a meaningful relationship.
那么模型描述的是有意义的关系